<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>plevy.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 13:38:26 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plevy.fr/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>TransFabriC - Institute of Circular Transfabrication</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/transfabric/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 13:38:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/transfabric/</guid><description>/ La TransFabriC / Institut de la transfabrication circulaire matérialise l&amp;rsquo;ambition du Conservatoire national des Arts et Métiers d&amp;rsquo;accompagner le développement des pratiques sociales et citoyennes pour l’émergence d’une économie sociale, solidaire et circulaire (ESSC). Il s&amp;rsquo;agit de créer un éco-système opérant, des formations et un programme de recherche, capables ensemble de faire émerger une ESSC répondant aux missions historiques du CNAM.
/ Éco-système /
Créer des lieux de mutualisation des pratiques de transformation de la matière (entreprises, ateliers, fablabs, labos, ressourceries&amp;hellip;)</description></item><item><title>Design apocalypse, a manifesto</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/design-apocalypse-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 10:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/design-apocalypse-manifesto/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Transforming Practices squad</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/transforming-practices-squad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 13:38:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/transforming-practices-squad/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Design lectures by Caroline Hummels</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/design-lecture-caroline-hummels/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/design-lecture-caroline-hummels/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Probing Future</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/probing-future/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/probing-future/</guid><description>How would our world look like 20, 30, 40 or 50 years from now? Will we monitor each individual on the planet to live a low-risk life? Will we replace organs, eyes, or other parts of our body with artificial alternatives? Will we upload our brains and live on a server? Or do we seek ways to embrace a life more related to mother earth? In this Design Fiction project, several potential healthcare futures are explored.</description></item><item><title>Stewart</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/stewart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/stewart/</guid><description>Stewart has received:
the Core77 award for best interaction design student work the Golden A’ design award in engineering and technical design Stewart is a tactile interface designed for a fully autonomous car. Self-driving cars offer obvious benefits such as faster travel and enhanced safety. However, they also eliminate a sense of freedom, expression, and control while driving.
Stewart’s objective is to accommodate a healthy relation between man and machine, to be achieved by an intuitive and expressive form of interaction.</description></item><item><title>Barely out of bed</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/haiku-cocoa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/haiku-cocoa/</guid><description>床を抜け
匙にて点てる
ココアの茶
Barely out of bed, · performing at the spoon · the brown of the hot chocolate
- Lévy (レヴィ) -</description></item><item><title>Kinectic Folds: Interaction Priming</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/kinectic-folds-interaction-priming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/kinectic-folds-interaction-priming/</guid><description>The prototype was inspired by the moment of perceptual crossing that occurs when you meet a stray cat in the street, and a moment of anticipation makes time stand still, as you and the cat try to figure each other out.Using a single sheet of folded paper and embedding it with motors and custom-built touch-capacitive sensors, an object which breathes and responds to the presence of human touch was designed, creating the perception that the Kinetic Fold is alive.</description></item><item><title>aGravity</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/agravity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/agravity/</guid><description>Nobody ever said that defying gravity is easy!
The aGravity is a device which lets one experience the challenge of levitation. The fingerboard allows one to float over a straight platform, while experiencing a constant evolving environment within. It creates unique interactions that makes one able to develop a new skill and improve over time. The aGravity aims to make more aware and sensitive to what is being perceived and how the slightest movement can influence the whole system.</description></item><item><title>Data Resonance</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/data-resonance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/data-resonance/</guid><description>What does data feel like? Data Resonance makes the table resonate with surrounding Wi-Fi traffic. Qualities of the digital signals are translated to something you can feel. This gives you a sense of activity at the workplace that is otherwise quiet and hidden. It creates a feedback loop about your own network usage, and a new connection with the activity of colleagues.
Data Resonance is inspired by how the traditional shared workshop acted as an extension of the craftsperson’s body.</description></item><item><title>Resonnant interaction</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/resonnant-interaction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/resonnant-interaction/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sensual Dynamics</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/sensual-dynamics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/sensual-dynamics/</guid><description>Prior to interaction, there is perception. Perception is intrinsically rising from one&amp;rsquo;s actions and from what one senses. These are the way one is connected to the world: acting is the way one impacts the world, sensing is the way one captures it. At this level, in direct contact with the world, there is no information, but energies (or forces). It is these energies and these forces that designers deal with (consciously or unconsciously) when putting a new artefact in the world.</description></item><item><title>Light in Transition</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/light-in-transition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/light-in-transition/</guid><description>We are accepting technology more and more into our lives as means to enhance the experience of the everyday. Intelligent products and systems are omnipresent, weave into our everyday life, and consequently have the power to transform our society. Adoption of these systems in our environments invites for exploring further how we interact with our environment.
This research is grounded on the phenomenology of perception and ecological psychology, considering perception to be active.</description></item><item><title>Luma</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/luma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/luma/</guid><description>This research project focuses on how to design for perceptive activity in artifacts in order for crossing in perception of expressivity between person and artifact to happen. It is part of the research of Deckers et al (2011), on designing for perceptual crossing between person and artifact. In their work they propose a series of design notions which are meant as a tool for synthesis when designing for perceptive activity in artifacts.</description></item><item><title>Monty</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/monty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/monty/</guid><description>Monty a curious entity that has the ability to perceive activity within its field of vision. When Monty detects activity it will gradually move towards the activity until it is in centre of its perception. If its interest is kept on the activity long enough, Monty becomes engaged and will start taking pictures of the activity.
The envisioned environment in which Monty can be used is a designer’s working environment. Here Monty will mainly be interested in the activity of the designer which will lead to process pictures of all the activities performed by this designer.</description></item><item><title>Passage</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/passage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/passage/</guid><description>Excerpt from my [Habilitation](/publications/time-of-experience/
Passage is a project carried out in 2012 by Gracia Goh, Chiyong Lim, and Kate Vermeyen at the Eindhoven University of Technology. Passage focuses on the place of transition between two physical spaces, i.e. their inter-space. The project statement invites students to create a design for the inter-space without influencing the experience of either space. This statement seems a priori phenomenologically incoherent, since the experience of something external to oneself necessarily takes place in a space and requires that the user’s attention be directed at least partially towards this thing.</description></item></channel></rss>