<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Not Knowing on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://plevy.fr/tags/not-knowing/</link><description>Recent content in Not Knowing on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>fr-FA</language><copyright>plevy.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:30:52 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plevy.fr/tags/not-knowing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>École du non-savoir</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/ecole-du-non-savoir/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:30:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/ecole-du-non-savoir/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/cahier-civic-city-3/"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/com.ulule.media/presales/2/3/5/1/8/1/181532/cahier-2.ByMQDN0o59.jpg" alt="Cahier" title="Cahier de l&amp;#39;école du non-savoir"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Les cahiers de l&amp;rsquo;école du non-savoir sont publiés et accessibles sur le site de &lt;a href="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/cahier-civic-city-3/"&gt;Civic City&lt;/a&gt; et sur &lt;a href="https://fr.ulule.com/civic-city/"&gt;Ulule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/post-HOME-ESTIENNE5.jpg" alt="nonsapere au Cnam" title="Poster pour la session au Cnam"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&amp;rsquo;école du non-savoir, a collaborative project and event with Civic-City, Ruedi Baur and Vera Bau, the Cnam&amp;rsquo;s Design Jean Prouvé chair (Pierre Lévy), the Institut Français and Estienne / École Supérieure des Arts et Industries Graphiques, is based on the conviction that dialogue between the arts, design, science and society can open up new horizons in our understanding and apprehension of known and yet-to-be-discovered worlds.
Through collaborative and evolving reflection, we question the mysteries and blind spots of today&amp;rsquo;s world and of worlds to come, our relationship with the known, the unknown, the hidden and the buried, questioning representations as well as modes of transmission of non-knowledge.
The aim is to imagine how design can give visibility to what is not visible, make perceptible what is not, and show what cannot be seen. To this end, it is bringing together experts and a network of 30 art and design schools from around the world to examine this non-knowledge together.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Séminaire de l'école du non-savoir</title><link>https://plevy.fr/events/seminaire-ecole-du-non-savoir/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/events/seminaire-ecole-du-non-savoir/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ce séminaire vise à lancer la troisième session de l&amp;rsquo;école du non-savoir. La première a débuté en septembre 2022 à l&amp;rsquo;Institut français de Milan et a abouti sous la forme d&amp;rsquo;une première exposition au même endroit en janvier 2024. Durant la seconde phase, l&amp;rsquo;exposition d&amp;rsquo;une centaine de panneaux a circulé à Florence et à Rome. De nouvelles écoles ont rejoint le projet initial en ajoutant de nouveaux visuels. Cet ensemble sera présenté à Porto dans le cadre de la Biennale du design à partir du 21 octobre 2023, avec le soutien de l&amp;rsquo;Institut français du Portugal.&lt;br&gt;
La troisième phase s&amp;rsquo;organise sur la base d&amp;rsquo;une trentaine d&amp;rsquo;écoles et d&amp;rsquo;universités, venant de France, d&amp;rsquo;Italie, du Portugal, d&amp;rsquo;Allemagne, de Pologne, d&amp;rsquo;Inde et de Madagascar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>