<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://plevy.fr/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in Design on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>plevy.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:30:52 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plevy.fr/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>School of not-knowing</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/school-of-not-knowing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:30:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/school-of-not-knowing/</guid><description>The school of not-knowing, a collaborative project and event with Civic-City, Ruedi Baur and Vera Bau, the Cnam&amp;rsquo;s Chaire of Design Jean Prouvé, the Institut Français and Estienne / École Supérieure des Arts et Industries Graphiques, is based on the conviction that dialogue between the arts, design, science and society can open up new horizons in our understanding and apprehension of known and yet-to-be-discovered worlds. Through collaborative and evolving reflection, we question the mysteries and blind spots of today&amp;rsquo;s world and of worlds to come, our relationship with the known, the unknown, the hidden and the buried, questioning representations as well as modes of transmission of non-knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Seminar of the school of not-knowing</title><link>https://plevy.fr/events/seminar-school-of-not-knowing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/events/seminar-school-of-not-knowing/</guid><description>This seminar aims to launch the third session of the school of not-Knowing. The first began in September 2022 at the French Institute in Milan and culminated in the form of a first exhibition in the same place in January 2024. During the second phase the exhibition of around a hundred panels circulated Florence and Rome. New schools joined the initial project by adding new visuals. This set will be presented in Porto as part of the Design Biennale from October 21, 2023, with the support of the French Institute of Portugal.</description></item><item><title>Chaire of Design Jean Prouvé</title><link>https://plevy.fr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/</guid><description>/ Inaugural lecture /
/ Recent writings / La diversité dans l&amp;rsquo;enseignement du design et des métiers d&amp;rsquo;art doit faire école / Programmes / Master in design in residence at the Academia of climate in Paris / Teaching / Design research (DSN201) · Reflective practices (DSN202) · Digital skills for professional transition (TET007) / Events / Research seminar Mediums in design with Annie Gentès, CY École de design / Projects / Scuola del non sapere with Ruedi Baur and Civic City · TransFabriC at CNAM</description></item><item><title>prof.dr.ing. Pierre Lévy, HDR</title><link>https://plevy.fr/pierre/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/pierre/</guid><description>Professor (PRCM) at National Conservatory of Arts and Crafts, France &amp;amp; Holder of the Chair of design Jean Prouvé
Pierre Lévy is a professor at the Conservatoire National des Arts et Métiers, holder of the Chair of design Jean Prouvé, and member of the Dicen-IDF laboratory (EA 7339). He holds an engineering degree in mechanical engineering (UT Compiègne, France), a Ph.D in kansei (affective) science (University of Tsukuba, Japan) and an HDR in information and communication sciences (UT Compiègne, France).</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>https://plevy.fr/projects/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/projects/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://plevy.fr/publications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/publications/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://plevy.fr/research/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/research/</guid><description>Japanese phylosophy inspired design Transforming practices Kansei studies Perceptive qualities The notion of perceptual crossing indicates the experience of interplay between perceptive activities of multiple beings (train anecdote). Charles Lenay explained the importance of perceptual crossing in the encounter of the other’s perceptual intentionality, in the mutual attraction of perceptual activities (“they come to start a sort of a dance together”), leading to the constitution of a shared world of emotions.</description></item></channel></rss>