<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Transforming_practices on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://plevy.fr/tags/transforming_practices/</link><description>Recent content in Transforming_practices on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>plevy.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plevy.fr/tags/transforming_practices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>prof.dr.ing. Pierre Lévy, HDR</title><link>https://plevy.fr/pierre/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/pierre/</guid><description>Professor (PRCM) at National Conservatory of Arts and Crafts, France &amp;amp; Holder of the Chair of design Jean Prouvé
Pierre Lévy is a professor at the Conservatoire National des Arts et Métiers, holder of the Chair of design Jean Prouvé, and member of the Dicen-IDF laboratory (EA 7339). He holds an engineering degree in mechanical engineering (UT Compiègne, France), a Ph.D in kansei (affective) science (University of Tsukuba, Japan) and an HDR in information and communication sciences (UT Compiègne, France).</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://plevy.fr/research/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/research/</guid><description>Japanese phylosophy inspired design Transforming practices Kansei studies Perceptive qualities The notion of perceptual crossing indicates the experience of interplay between perceptive activities of multiple beings (train anecdote). Charles Lenay explained the importance of perceptual crossing in the encounter of the other’s perceptual intentionality, in the mutual attraction of perceptual activities (“they come to start a sort of a dance together”), leading to the constitution of a shared world of emotions.</description></item></channel></rss>