<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Not Knowing on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/tags/not-knowing/</link><description>Recent content in Not Knowing on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-GB</language><copyright>plevy.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:30:52 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plevy.fr/en/tags/not-knowing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>School of not-knowing</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/school-of-not-knowing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:30:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/school-of-not-knowing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/cahier-civic-city-3/"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/com.ulule.media/presales/2/3/5/1/8/1/181532/cahier-2.ByMQDN0o59.jpg" alt="Cahier" title="Cahier de l&amp;#39;école du non-savoir"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Les cahiers de l&amp;rsquo;école du non-savoir sont publiés et accessibles sur le site de &lt;a href="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/cahier-civic-city-3/"&gt;Civic City&lt;/a&gt; et sur &lt;a href="https://fr.ulule.com/civic-city/"&gt;Ulule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/post-HOME-ESTIENNE5.jpg" alt="nonsapere au Cnam" title="Poster pour la session au Cnam"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&amp;rsquo;école du non-savoir, a collaborative project and event with Civic-City, Ruedi Baur and Vera Bau, the Cnam&amp;rsquo;s Design Jean Prouvé chair (Pierre Lévy), the Institut Français and Estienne / École Supérieure des Arts et Industries Graphiques, is based on the conviction that dialogue between the arts, design, science and society can open up new horizons in our understanding and apprehension of known and yet-to-be-discovered worlds.
Through collaborative and evolving reflection, we question the mysteries and blind spots of today&amp;rsquo;s world and of worlds to come, our relationship with the known, the unknown, the hidden and the buried, questioning representations as well as modes of transmission of non-knowledge.
The aim is to imagine how design can give visibility to what is not visible, make perceptible what is not, and show what cannot be seen. To this end, it is bringing together experts and a network of 30 art and design schools from around the world to examine this non-knowledge together.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Seminar of the school of not-knowing</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/events/seminar-school-of-not-knowing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/events/seminar-school-of-not-knowing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This seminar aims to launch the third session of the school of not-Knowing. The first began in September 2022 at the French Institute in Milan and culminated in the form of a first exhibition in the same place in January 2024. During the second phase the exhibition of around a hundred panels circulated Florence and Rome. New schools joined the initial project by adding new visuals. This set will be presented in Porto as part of the Design Biennale from October 21, 2023, with the support of the French Institute of Portugal.&lt;br&gt;
The third phase is being organized on the basis of around thirty schools and universities, coming from France, Italy, Portugal, Germany, Poland, India and Madagascar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>