<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-GB</language><copyright>plevy.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:30:52 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plevy.fr/en/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>School of not-knowing</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/school-of-not-knowing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:30:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/school-of-not-knowing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/cahier-civic-city-3/"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/com.ulule.media/presales/2/3/5/1/8/1/181532/cahier-2.ByMQDN0o59.jpg" alt="Cahier" title="Cahier de l&amp;#39;école du non-savoir"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Les cahiers de l&amp;rsquo;école du non-savoir sont publiés et accessibles sur le site de &lt;a href="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/cahier-civic-city-3/"&gt;Civic City&lt;/a&gt; et sur &lt;a href="https://fr.ulule.com/civic-city/"&gt;Ulule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/post-HOME-ESTIENNE5.jpg" alt="nonsapere au Cnam" title="Poster pour la session au Cnam"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&amp;rsquo;école du non-savoir, a collaborative project and event with Civic-City, Ruedi Baur and Vera Bau, the Cnam&amp;rsquo;s Design Jean Prouvé chair (Pierre Lévy), the Institut Français and Estienne / École Supérieure des Arts et Industries Graphiques, is based on the conviction that dialogue between the arts, design, science and society can open up new horizons in our understanding and apprehension of known and yet-to-be-discovered worlds.
Through collaborative and evolving reflection, we question the mysteries and blind spots of today&amp;rsquo;s world and of worlds to come, our relationship with the known, the unknown, the hidden and the buried, questioning representations as well as modes of transmission of non-knowledge.
The aim is to imagine how design can give visibility to what is not visible, make perceptible what is not, and show what cannot be seen. To this end, it is bringing together experts and a network of 30 art and design schools from around the world to examine this non-knowledge together.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>TransFabriC - Institute of Circular Transfabrication</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/transfabric/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 13:38:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/transfabric/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This research-action project through design, proposes to study and follow the development of the practice of professionals related to the recovery, transformation, and valorization of unused materials and goods (from HESAM members: Cnam workshops, art and engineering schools or from associations associated with the place), as well as that of non-expert citizens within the circular and sociale economie [1]. Through the implementation of socio-technical systems for the SSCE, the aim is to understand the means (devices and situated practices) by which repair or appropriation, considered as creative activities contributing to current societal, ecological chllenges [2] are made possible, and to value them in the practices of eco-responsible design and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Design apocalypse, a manifesto</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/design-apocalypse-manifesto/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 10:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/design-apocalypse-manifesto/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Transforming Practices squad</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/transforming-practices-squad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 13:38:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/transforming-practices-squad/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Design lectures by Caroline Hummels</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/design-lecture-caroline-hummels/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/design-lecture-caroline-hummels/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Probing Future</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/probing-future/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/probing-future/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;How would our world look like 20, 30, 40 or 50 years from now? Will we monitor each individual on the planet to live a low-risk life? Will we replace organs, eyes, or other parts of our body with artificial alternatives? Will we upload our brains and live on a server? Or do we seek ways to embrace a life more related to mother earth? In this Design Fiction project, several potential healthcare futures are explored. The project is a collaboration between Philips Design, Eindhoven University of Technology, Design Academy Eindhoven, and Frank Kolkman.&lt;br&gt;
When designing and developing for an audience, as was done in this project, a wide range of different opinions have to be dealt with. A well-known example are robots and Artificial intelligence (AI). Some people only see the positive side and potentials: what if robots could take over all our work so we have full-time vacation? Others only see the downsides and risks: what if robots become smarter than people and start attacking us? Either way, the truth will be somewhere in the middle, but it is very important to capture such opinions and discover what society thinks of current developments. The goal of this project was to do exactly that by developing design probes for four potential healthcare futures – based on a framework by Philips Design – and exhibiting them during the Dutch Design Week (DDW) and within Philips to provoke a debate.&lt;br&gt;
During the first part of the project, four teams each developed a design probe for one of the potential futures, which were exhibited at the Dutch Design Week.&lt;br&gt;
The project was continued within another team and a fifth probe was designed based on the insights gathered at the DDW. This time, the focus was laid on preventive healthcare in the present time, which led to the design of a fictive device that helps parents to monitor their baby’s health and aids them in growing a healthy child.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stewart</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/stewart/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/stewart/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Stewart has received:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Core77 award for best interaction design student work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Golden A’ design award in engineering and technical design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stewart is a tactile interface designed for a fully autonomous car. Self-driving cars offer obvious benefits such as faster travel and enhanced safety. However, they also eliminate a sense of freedom, expression, and control while driving.&lt;br&gt;
Stewart’s objective is to accommodate a healthy relation between man and machine, to be achieved by an intuitive and expressive form of interaction.&lt;br&gt;
Stewart provides you with constant updates about the car’s behaviour and its intentions. If you don’t agree on the car’s next course of action, you can manipulate Stewart to change this. Stewart will learn from you as you can learn from Stewart, hopefully resulting in a mutually trustful relation.&lt;br&gt;
Interaction through Stewart will bring about a haptic discussion about what the car’s next move will be. Who will win this discussion? Who knows best?&lt;br&gt;
Stewart is on: core77 | Design News | BBC | Creative Applications Network | and many other places…&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Barely out of bed</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/haiku-cocoa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/haiku-cocoa/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;床を抜け&lt;br&gt;
匙にて点てる&lt;br&gt;
ココアの茶&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barely out of bed, · performing at the spoon · the brown of the hot chocolate&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- Lévy (レヴィ) -&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Kinectic Folds: Interaction Priming</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/kinectic-folds-interaction-priming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/kinectic-folds-interaction-priming/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The prototype was inspired by the moment of perceptual crossing that occurs when you meet a stray cat in the street, and a moment of anticipation makes time stand still, as you and the cat try to figure each other out.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Using a single sheet of folded paper and embedding it with motors and custom-built touch-capacitive sensors, an object which breathes and responds to the presence of human touch was designed, creating the perception that the Kinetic Fold is alive.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>aGravity</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/agravity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/agravity/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nobody ever said that defying gravity is easy!&lt;br&gt;
The aGravity is a device which lets one experience the challenge of levitation. The fingerboard allows one to float over a straight platform, while experiencing a constant evolving environment within. It creates unique interactions that makes one able to develop a new skill and improve over time. The aGravity aims to make more aware and sensitive to what is being perceived and how the slightest movement can influence the whole system.&lt;br&gt;
To get the board hovering, requires focus, concentration and some skill. Though once it is learned to hover the board, it is up to the user how far he or she can go. Giving no precise guidelines, the only rule is to explore, interact and challenge yourself.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- Alex Jurtan -&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Data Resonance</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/data-resonance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/data-resonance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What does data feel like? Data Resonance makes the table resonate with surrounding Wi-Fi traffic. Qualities of the digital signals are translated to something you can feel. This gives you a sense of activity at the workplace that is otherwise quiet and hidden. It creates a feedback loop about your own network usage, and a new connection with the activity of colleagues.&lt;br&gt;
Data Resonance is inspired by how the traditional shared workshop acted as an extension of the craftsperson’s body. You saw and heard your colleagues work, and awareness of their activity influenced what you did. Now that much of our creative work happens on the screen, we lost something. With Data Resonance, we become more aware again of colleague’s work in a calm way: we notice when someone is dealing with heavy traffic and when people are taking a break, or just tune in to the rhythms of data that flow through space.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- Sander Dijkhuis -&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Resonnant interaction</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/resonnant-interaction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/resonnant-interaction/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sensual Dynamics</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/sensual-dynamics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/sensual-dynamics/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Prior to interaction, there is perception. Perception is intrinsically rising from one&amp;rsquo;s actions and from what one senses. These are the way one is connected to the world: acting is the way one impacts the world, sensing is the way one captures it. At this level, in direct contact with the world, there is no information, but energies (or forces). It is these energies and these forces that designers deal with (consciously or unconsciously) when putting a new artefact in the world. This primacy of perception towards interaction is the main focus of this workshop, proposing an approach to effectively taking it into consideration in the design process.&lt;br&gt;
For design practical reasons, design should focus on qualities of senses. For example, touching is local, reciprocal, and private. It is where I touch, I am touched by what I am touching, and nobody else can touch what I touch. On the other hand, smell is at a distance, possibly unidirectional, and public. These are qualities of senses that can be useful for design. To be so, these qualities need to determined and mapped. Moreover, we may seek differences between static and dynamics qualities of senses.&lt;br&gt;
Finally, designers should comprehend these qualities and engage them in order to find opportunities for design - how can I make something private at a distance? How can techno challenge these qualities (e.g. headphones make sound private)? What implications for design?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Light in Transition</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/light-in-transition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/light-in-transition/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are accepting technology more and more into our lives as means to enhance the experience of the everyday. Intelligent products and systems are omnipresent, weave into our everyday life, and consequently have the power to transform our society. Adoption of these systems in our environments invites for exploring further how we interact with our environment.&lt;br&gt;
This research is grounded on the phenomenology of perception and ecological psychology, considering perception to be active. Perception is result of the dynamic coupling between a person’s action in relation to her or his environment and the sensory input this environment provides. In other words, we have to act to perceive and we concentrate our senses in the direction of the stimuli: e.g., turn our body around to see what is behind us, in order to perceive.&lt;br&gt;
The research focuses on how interaction with interactive artefacts can add intrinsic value on space being experienced as a transitory space. Four topics are introduced to investigate our experience of space as transitory space: ritual, space, light and craft. They serve as the backbone of the project and we could say that the ritual is the means for the technology (light) to enable the value (sense of place) to emerge in interaction with (hand) crafted artefacts. In this project I investigate if an interactive lighting installation can trigger our sense of place and belonging in spaces.&lt;br&gt;
Throughout this project I follow a ‘research-through-design’ approach. This is an approach where products are designed to explore implications of theory in context. The idea of perceptive qualities in interactive lighting installations is explored, and I question if an interactive artefact contributes to the experience of transition and allows for a greater feeling of involvement in the space. The project is divided into three cases:&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Luma</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/luma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/luma/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This research project focuses on how to design for perceptive activity in artifacts in order for crossing in perception of expressivity between person and artifact to happen. It is part of the research of Deckers et al (2011), on designing for perceptual crossing between person and artifact. In their work they propose a series of design notions which are meant as a tool for synthesis when designing for perceptive activity in artifacts. In this research we follow a research through design approach in order to generate design specific knowledge on the application of these design notions when designing an artifact capable of showing expressivity through its perceptive behavior. We designed LUMA, an dynamic light design capable of expressing a variable level of excitement thought its perceptive actions. We conducted research using the LUMA design in order to investigate how the stage of perception of expressivity can be reached in an artifact and if crossing of perception of expressivity can happen over the course of interaction between person and artifact. For this we specifically investigate the relation between the perceived expressivity and the occurrence of a cross-influential interplay of expressivity between person and artifact. The results of our experiment show that clarity in variability of this expression is essential for this interplay to occur. We discuss possible changes to the design to improve the clarity in variability of expressivity as well as further research steps.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- Koen Beljaars -&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Monty</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/monty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/monty/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Monty a curious entity that has the ability to perceive activity within its field of vision. When Monty detects activity it will gradually move towards the activity until it is in centre of its perception. If its interest is kept on the activity long enough, Monty becomes engaged and will start taking pictures of the activity.&lt;br&gt;
The envisioned environment in which Monty can be used is a designer’s working environment. Here Monty will mainly be interested in the activity of the designer which will lead to process pictures of all the activities performed by this designer. This in turn gives the designer the possibility to reflect on his own process by scrolling through the visual representation of his activities. And will give him process pictures that can be used for communicative purposes.&lt;br&gt;
Due to its curious nature Monty might not always be focused on what you are doing. He can however be temporarily motivated to move towards a particular area on your desk.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- Rens Alkemade -&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Passage</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/passage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/passage/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excerpt from my &lt;a href="https://plevy.fr/publications/time-of-experience/"&gt;Habilitation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passage is a project carried out in 2012 by Gracia Goh, Chiyong Lim, and Kate Vermeyen at the Eindhoven University of Technology. Passage focuses on the place of transition between two physical spaces, i.e. their inter-space. The project statement invites students to create a design for the inter-space without influencing the experience of either space. This statement seems a priori phenomenologically incoherent, since the experience of something external to oneself necessarily takes place in a space and requires that the user’s attention be directed at least partially towards this thing. Yet, not only does the inter-space not seem to be a space (but rather a surface), and the attention of a person passing through a door is most often directed towards the space in which they intend to travel.&lt;br&gt;
After multiple iterations including prototype production, situation tests, reflections based on the Kansei context, etc., a remarkable design has gradually taken shape. Passage is an installation mounted on the frame of a door. This installation consists of a line of light-emitting diodes (RGB LEDs) projected on a thin aluminium foil that reflects light back towards the door once it is ajar. The diodes very slowly change the emitted color. The aluminium foil undulates depending on how the door is opened: a quick opening will create much more turbulence than a slow opening. The light impression projected on the door is therefore unique with each opening and closing.&lt;br&gt;
What is remarkable about this design is that the light projection is not visible to the passer-by when the door is fully closed or open, so that interaction only takes place in the action of the door opening. The experience begins as soon as you start opening the door and ends before you finish opening it. Not only is the installation (almost) located in this inter-space, but the experience is also located in this inter-space: it almost does not interfere with the passer-by’s intentionality to pass into the next space. The design objective is thus achieved.&lt;br&gt;
In addition to certain “classical” kansei descriptors, such as the grain, the light-shade interaction or the feeling of an invitation to appreciate this inter-space, kansei descriptors specific to this project have been established: instantaneity and the elusive, and even more so their couple. What is remarkable is that this experience is engaging from the point of view of its expression, engaging by the gesture, and that its intensity comes from the fact that it is very short, unavoidable, and elusive: in an instant it engages us then liberates us, without us being able to really escape it, or do anything about it. That is the beauty of this design.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>