<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rituel on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://plevy.fr/tags/rituel/</link><description>Recent content in Rituel on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>fr-FA</language><copyright>plevy.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:55:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plevy.fr/tags/rituel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Designing for the everyday</title><link>https://plevy.fr/teaching/designing-for-the-everyday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/teaching/designing-for-the-everyday/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The everyday is the reality in which we act and perceive through unremarkable experiences. It is about going to sleep, waking up, cleaning, eating, dressing and undressing, reading, drinking tea or coffee… It is therefore in the flow of the infraordinary (Perec, 1989) and the banal, away of the extraordinary and of the memorable. What the everyday is actually less a matter of activity value than a matter of ‘specific mode of manifestation’ (Dewolf, 2008).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Composing Everyday Rituals</title><link>https://plevy.fr/teaching/composing-everyday-rituals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 14:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/teaching/composing-everyday-rituals/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Our lives are a collection of rituals. The way we wake up, the way we leave or enter our home, the way we prepare our suitcase before going on a trip are just simple examples of the many rituals each of us have constructed and that structure our everyday lives. These rituals are not rigid procedures, but a seemingly established series of activities from which experiential meaning emerges, and by which personal values are expressed.
The aim of this course is to address these qualities embodied in rituals from an interaction design perspective, and to explore the relation between the designed artefacts and the rituals they are involved in. Through this exploration, we will gain insights in the relational nature of these influences between the artefacts, subjects, and the ritual (and by extension the experiential meanings and the expressed values). The main focus will be on how to capture, to clarify, and to compose rituals. The final discussion will address the merits of addressing rituals in interaction design, and how to design for meaningful rituals.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>