<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in Design on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-GB</language><copyright>plevy.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 10:04:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plevy.fr/en/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Seminar on methods in design research</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/events/seminaire-de-recherche-en-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 10:04:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/events/seminaire-de-recherche-en-design/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The ‘Research practices in design and creation’ methodology seminar is organised and run jointly by the Dicen-IDF laboratory and the Jean Prouvé Design Chair at the National Conservatory of Arts and Craft (Cnam). Primarily aimed at master&amp;rsquo;s students, young researchers, doctoral candidates and those aspiring to become such, it invites members of research communities linked to the fields of design and creation to contribute together to a better understanding of the methodological issues involved in research as a place for exploration, discussion and the dissemination of ideas and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Le design est-il une science humaine ?</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/events/le-design-est-il-une-science-humaine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/events/le-design-est-il-une-science-humaine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Au sein de l’École Estienne, SEMPER* constitue un espace d’intersection et de réflexion commun aux quatre parcours de formation en DSAA. Le séminaire, initié par Jérôme Duwa, Olivier Moulin et Carole Papion invite à réfléchir et à mettre en valeur ce qui se constitue comme recherche en design dans le milieu qui est le nôtre à l’École Estienne : expériences en imprimerie, dans les métiers d’art, dans les domaines du graphisme, de l’illustration, de la création numérique, de la typographie et de la stratégie de communication.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>School of not-knowing</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/school-of-not-knowing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:30:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/projects/school-of-not-knowing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/cahier-civic-city-3/"&gt;&lt;img src="https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/com.ulule.media/presales/2/3/5/1/8/1/181532/cahier-2.ByMQDN0o59.jpg" alt="Cahier" title="Cahier de l&amp;#39;école du non-savoir"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Les cahiers de l&amp;rsquo;école du non-savoir sont publiés et accessibles sur le site de &lt;a href="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/cahier-civic-city-3/"&gt;Civic City&lt;/a&gt; et sur &lt;a href="https://fr.ulule.com/civic-city/"&gt;Ulule&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://civic-city.org/nonsapere/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/post-HOME-ESTIENNE5.jpg" alt="nonsapere au Cnam" title="Poster pour la session au Cnam"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;L&amp;rsquo;école du non-savoir, a collaborative project and event with Civic-City, Ruedi Baur and Vera Bau, the Cnam&amp;rsquo;s Design Jean Prouvé chair (Pierre Lévy), the Institut Français and Estienne / École Supérieure des Arts et Industries Graphiques, is based on the conviction that dialogue between the arts, design, science and society can open up new horizons in our understanding and apprehension of known and yet-to-be-discovered worlds.
Through collaborative and evolving reflection, we question the mysteries and blind spots of today&amp;rsquo;s world and of worlds to come, our relationship with the known, the unknown, the hidden and the buried, questioning representations as well as modes of transmission of non-knowledge.
The aim is to imagine how design can give visibility to what is not visible, make perceptible what is not, and show what cannot be seen. To this end, it is bringing together experts and a network of 30 art and design schools from around the world to examine this non-knowledge together.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Seminar of the school of not-knowing</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/events/seminar-school-of-not-knowing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/events/seminar-school-of-not-knowing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This seminar aims to launch the third session of the school of not-Knowing. The first began in September 2022 at the French Institute in Milan and culminated in the form of a first exhibition in the same place in January 2024. During the second phase the exhibition of around a hundred panels circulated Florence and Rome. New schools joined the initial project by adding new visuals. This set will be presented in Porto as part of the Design Biennale from October 21, 2023, with the support of the French Institute of Portugal.&lt;br&gt;
The third phase is being organized on the basis of around thirty schools and universities, coming from France, Italy, Portugal, Germany, Poland, India and Madagascar.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chaire of design Jean Prouvé</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Chaire of Design Jean Prouvé</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/chaire/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/chaire/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Jean Prouvé Chair in Design is a welcoming space dedicated to developing the role of design practice and research in society and culture. Its focus is on expressing beauty through everyday materials and reflective practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/publications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/publications/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Research</title><link>https://plevy.fr/en/research/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/en/research/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="japanese-phylosophy-inspired-design"&gt;Japanese phylosophy inspired design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="transforming-practices"&gt;Transforming practices&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="kansei-studies"&gt;Kansei studies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="perceptive-qualities"&gt;Perceptive qualities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The notion of perceptual crossing indicates the experience of interplay between perceptive activities of multiple beings (train anecdote). Charles Lenay explained the importance of perceptual crossing in the encounter of the other’s perceptual intentionality, in the mutual attraction of perceptual activities (“they come to start a sort of a dance together”), leading to the constitution of a shared world of emotions. Creating such a connection between beings is often experienced, and it is (and it has been for a long time) a quest in design to build such connection between a being (or user) and an artefact: how to design for perceptual crossing?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>