<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Enseignements on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/</link><description>Recent content in Enseignements on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>fr</language><copyright>plevy.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 20:03:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Master Design &lt;br/> Création, Projet, Transdisciplinarité</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/master_design-creation_projet_transdisciplinarite/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/master_design-creation_projet_transdisciplinarite/</guid><description>You are being redirected to the Notion page.</description></item><item><title>M2-TNIC &lt;br/> Reflexions en design</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/m2-tnic-reflexions_en_design/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/m2-tnic-reflexions_en_design/</guid><description>You are being redirected to the Notion page.</description></item><item><title>TET007-M1 &lt;br/> Approche pratique du numérique et la recherche d'information</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/tet007-m1-approche_pratique_du_numerique_et_la_recherche_d_information/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/tet007-m1-approche_pratique_du_numerique_et_la_recherche_d_information/</guid><description/></item><item><title>TET007-RNCP &lt;br/> Approche pratique du numérique et la recherche d'information</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/tet007-rncp-approche_pratique_du_numerique_et_la_recherche_d_information/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/tet007-rncp-approche_pratique_du_numerique_et_la_recherche_d_information/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Matter of Transformation</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/matter-of-transformation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/matter-of-transformation/</guid><description>Description This elective invites students to consider and deepen (both hands-on and through reflection) their understanding of the relationship between aesthetics and various concepts from human sciences that are at stake in the design process for transformation, including philosophy, psychology, sociology and economics.
For this aim, three frameworks are introduced and discussed (examples): complex thinking, learning, lenses &amp; perspectives, embodied theories, post-phenomenology, transition theories. Throughout the elective, students analyse the implication of these frameworks on the designs they create (as aesthetics propositions), and of designs on these frameworks.</description></item><item><title>Designing for the everyday</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/designing-for-the-everyday/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/designing-for-the-everyday/</guid><description>Description The everyday is the reality in which we act and perceive through unremarkable experiences. It is about going to sleep, waking up, cleaning, eating, dressing and undressing, reading, drinking tea or coffee… It is therefore in the flow of the infraordinary (Perec, 1989) and the banal, away of the extraordinary and of the memorable. What the everyday is actually less a matter of activity value than a matter of ‘specific mode of manifestation’ (Dewolf, 2008).</description></item><item><title>Composing Everyday Rituals</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/composing-everyday-rituals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 14:55:28 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/composing-everyday-rituals/</guid><description>Description Our lives are a collection of rituals. The way we wake up, the way we leave or enter our home, the way we prepare our suitcase before going on a trip are just simple examples of the many rituals each of us have constructed and that structure our everyday lives. These rituals are not rigid procedures, but a seemingly established series of activities from which experiential meaning emerges, and by which personal values are expressed.</description></item><item><title>Designing rituals</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/designing-rituals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/designing-rituals/</guid><description>Our lives are a collection of rituals. The way we wake up, the way we leave or enter our home, the way we prepare our suitcase before going on a trip are just simple examples of the many rituals each of us have constructed and that structure our everyday lives. These rituals are not rigid procedures, but a seemingly established series of activities from which experiential meaning emerges, and by which personal values are expressed.</description></item><item><title>Designing Quality in Interaction theory</title><link>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/dqi-theory/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://plevy.fr/fr/teaching/dqi-theory/</guid><description>In this two-week workshop, theories of interaction design are explained and explored through applications. The DQI approach to Interaction Design is theory informed. This means that theory inspires and even guides the way we look at interaction, and the way we design for interaction and experience.
Topics - Phenomenology and experience (Merlau-Ponty and Dewey)
- Gibsonian theory of perception
- Models of interaction: Interaction Frogger
- Resonance
- Rich Interaction</description></item></channel></rss>