<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Interaction on Pierre Lévy</title><link>https://chaire-design.fr/en/tags/interaction/</link><description>Recent content in Interaction on Pierre Lévy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-GB</language><copyright>chaire-design.fr</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:27:15 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chaire-design.fr/en/tags/interaction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Design 3.0 Forum</title><link>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/design-30-forum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/design-30-forum/</guid><description>&lt;h3 class="text-epierrot">DESIGN 3.0 FORUM&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Introduction by &lt;strong>Dr. Ki-Young Nam, KAIST&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
Congratulatory Remark by &lt;strong>Prof. Kun-pyo Lee&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Professor Rachel Cooper, Lancaster University&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
| Context-setting for the theme: Design for Public Sector and Social Innovation&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Professor Martyn Evans, MMU&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
| Design for policy&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Dr. Edward Hyunwook Hwangbo, PDR&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
| Design for policy&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Dr. Pierre Levy, TU Einthoven&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
| Interaction design for society&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Professor John Vines, Northumbria University&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
| Digital civics&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contemplating the impossible</title><link>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/contemplating-the-impossible/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 10:30:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/contemplating-the-impossible/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First, I would like to thank Stephan Wensveen for the organisation and for making this day a such a special one, from start to end (although who knows how it will end…).&lt;br>
I am very glad to be here. It is an honour to participate to this symposium, and to have the role of opening the series of presentations. It is also a challenge I must say. Kees has been enriching the life of many of us, and I believe many of us would have something valuable to tell based on sharing experiences with Kees. I am very conscious of this privilege.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kees Overbeeke symposium</title><link>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/kees-overbeeke-symposium/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/kees-overbeeke-symposium/</guid><description>&lt;p>Stephan was appointed full professor of ‘Constructive Design Research in Smart Products, Services and Systems’ in the Department of Industrial Design on May 1, 2017. He will deliver his inaugural lecture ‘Constructive Design Research’ at 16:00.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, there will be a series of lectures by staff and students including Pierre Levy, Caroline Hummels, Luke Noothout and Angella Mackey.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Guest speakers include Bill Gaver, from the University of London, who will give a talk describing how he and his team has designed DIY devices that people can make themselves: ‘The first is for a collection of cameras and an audio device designed for Cultural Probes studies. The second, a ‘wildlife’ camera that uses computer vision to trigger image capture when it sees movement.’&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The bases of direct interaction design</title><link>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/the-bases-of-direct-interaction-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 21:39:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/the-bases-of-direct-interaction-design/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Direct interaction design</title><link>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/direct-interaction-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 21:29:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/direct-interaction-design/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Light through Culture - Experience Human Rights</title><link>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/light-through-culture/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 16:27:15 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://chaire-design.fr/en/events/light-through-culture/</guid><description>&lt;p>Light through Culture is an international design school which explores the theme of complexity in learning environments. The aim of the school is to weave the newest technologies and the rich existing culture into a new canvas for making and thinking. The school was funded in 2011 by Patrizia Marti (University of Siena) and Kees Overbeeke (Technical University of Eindhoven).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This ehibition proposes a reflection on the individual vs. social perception of human rights, exploring 2 fundamental and controverted articles of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. Article 13: Everyone has the right to freedom of movement and residence within the borders of each state. Everyone has the right to leave any country, including his own, and to return to his country. Article 19: Everyone has the right to freedom of opinion and expression; this right includes freedom to hold opinions without interference and to seek, receive and impart information and ideas through any media and regardless of frontiers. Visitors travel through an interactive path, where they experience the application or the negation of such rights. This concurs in stimulating and reinforcing a reflection on their relevance and universality.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>